### JUAN CAMILO ROBERTO MONTEJO CAICEDO

### juancamiloroberto@gmail.com

Cel 57-301-2553796 Home 57-2-3754284

#### PROFILE

A graduate of the Master in Business Administration (MBA) U. of the Andes, at Colombia, with more than 20 years of experience in High Technology, Telecommunications and Financial sectors, both in USA and Latin America.

My area of expertise include: Finance (Quantitative Finance, Risk and Investment Banking), and Corporate Strategy.

I enjoy studying and working with executives and professionals, leading and negotiating highly complex projects.

Besides my experience in the Real and Financial Sectors, I spend good time in Teaching and Consulting.

#### **EDUCATION**

1994	MBA (Master in Business Administration.) Major in Finance Universidad de los Andes, Bogota DC, Colombia
1993	Electrical Engineer Major in Electronics and Computers. Universidad Autónoma de Occidente Cali, Colombia
1989	System Engineer. Major in Software Engineering. ICESI University Cali, Colombia

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

INVESTMENT BANKING-FINANCIAL CORPORATE CONSULTING Bogotá 2009 – Present Investment Banking Private Boutique

#### **General Manager – Senior Financial Consultant**

Responsible for the creation and implementation of the company

CRCBMC SA Bogotá 2008-2009 Clearing House of BMC

#### President & CEO

Responsible for the transformation, growth and Corporate IT update. Main Achievement: Leading technological modernization of the company.

## Universidad Autónoma de Occidente Cali 2004-2008

### **Director Program Management-Dual-mode Berufsakademie**

Responsible for the launch, development and growth of the new career.

Main Achievement Award for academic excellence and CERTQUA (Germany)

2005 until 2008.

## Universidad Jorge Tadeo Lozano-Sectional Caribbean Cartagena 2004

#### **Dean Management School**

Responsible for the development of the several programs of undergraduate and graduate School of Management.

Main Achievement: Record Delivery programs Qualified Management Area.

### Pontificia Universidad Javeriana Cali 2000 - 2003

### Director of the Specialization in Finance

University Professor of Undergraduate and Postgraduate in the area of Finance.

Main Achievement: Regional Position in Finance.

### Lucent Technologies USA 1998 - 2000

#### Caribbean and Latin America, Y2K (Year 2000) Customer Team Manager.

Latin American level executive, responsible for implementing the 2000 strategy for the various client platforms in the Caribbean and Latin America.

Main Achievement: CALA 2000 President's Excellence Award for outstanding performance.

### IBM de Colombia Bogotá DC 1996 - 1998

## TSM Andean Engagement Leader - PSS (Product Support Services) Nov. 1997 - July 1998.

Led new business TSM (Total System Management), integrating and selling the portfolio of services from IBM after sales for the entire Andean region.

Main achievement: the opening of a new market with an innovative portfolio in the Andean Region.

## Marketing Financial Advisor (Finance Division) May 1996 - Nov. 1997.

Responsible for the design and sale of IBM's financial products to our customers.

Main Achievement: exceeded the goals of funding for Colombia and the Andean Region.

## **Engagement Manager. (Outsourcing Division) July 1995 - May 1996**

Structure financial solutions outsourcing various IBM businesses in Colombia. Main Achievement: Led and closed the biggest deal at that time associated with outsourcing to IBM data centers in Colombia (US.12.5 mill. 5-year contract with South American HS)

## Financorp SA Cali - Colombia

### CFO-Finance VP 1995

Leader of the financial strategy at the country level.

Main achievement: Member of executive leadership team, who creates and builds the company.

### Mazda Credit SA Bogotá DC - Colombia

### Country Commercial Manager and VP 1994

Executive in charge of marketing and sales operation of the company. Focused primarily on leasing and credit.

Main Achievement: Entering the Colombian financial markets with a new lease 70-30 nationwide. We put about Col.\$ 33.000 mill (US\$16.5 mill) in three months.

#### IT Consultancy

Cali-Colombia

**IT Senior Consultant** 

1988-1993

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

Teaching experience in Finance in undergraduate and postgraduate.

#### Universidad de Cuenca - Ecuador

#### 2006-2007

Theory of Financial Risk Strategic Management Financial Engineering

## Universidad del Valle 2005 -2010

Investment Portfolio Financial Risk Management Specialization in Finance

### San Buenaventura University 2004

Investment Banking

## Universidad Javeriana - Cali 2000-2003

- Economic Engineering
- Financial Mathematics
- Strategic Management
- Finance (Basic and Applied)
- Evaluation, Planning and Project Management
- Investment Portfolio.
- Financial Management
- Financial Services
- Financial Markets
- Financial Engineering
- Capital Markets
- International Finance

### Universidad Autónoma de Occidente

### Cali

### 2000-2003

- Project Evaluation
- Economic Engineering
- Investments

### Universidad Javeriana Bogotá

### 1994

Sales Marketing

Seminar "Management of Competitiveness

### Universidad de los Andes Bogotá

1994

Graduate Research Assistant: Faculty of Engineering - CIFI Monitor-MBA Quantitative Methods

### Universidad de la Salle Bogotá

1994

Sales Management

Finance I, II MBA Management

### Universidad Autónoma de Occidente

Cali 1993

Data Structures in Turbo Pascal Applied Computer Engineering

#### **ICESI University**

Cali 2011

Investment Portfolio-MBA 1989-1990

"General Systems Theory"

### **CONSULTING EXPERIENCE**

### INVESTMENT BANKING Bogota and Cali 2009-Present

- Financial Diagnostics Corporate Media Group
- Business Feasibility Study "gravel" for construction
- Diagnosis, assessment and transfer fruit exporter
- Achieving international bond purchase oil drilling
- Investment Consulting public projects
- Analysis & Development new products on commodities
- Consultancy for engineering company
- Building new business for a large bank
- Private consultant for a stockbroker

### RWD Cali-Bogota 2006

Consultancy for evaluation of potential customers.

### STRATEGIUM SLC NOVUS

Cali-Bogota

2005-2006

Consulting and positioning leads

BVC-Bolsa De Valores de Colombia Banco de Occidente-Corfivalle CMC-Center for Capital Market Development Cali 2004

"Instruments Fixed Income Valuation and Risk-Bonds

"Financial Risk Management"

### BVC-Bolsa De Valores de Colombia (Stock Exchange) CMC-Center for Capital Market Development Cali 2002

"Instruments Fixed Income Valuation and Risk-Bonds

### Interaction (Broker) and Coomeva Cali

2002

Investment Portfolio Structure

### BVC-Bolsa De Valores de Colombia (Stock Exchange) Cali 2001

- Financial Risk Management Seminar
- "Valuation of Securities"

### **Grupo Empresarial Bavaria**

**Bogotá DC** 

1994 - 1995

Consulting "Sales and Marketing Training"

## Montejo Vega & Cia. - Engineers - Architects Cali

1991-1993

- Consulting
- Define, structure and implement information processes.

### Private Consultant - SUGAR SECTOR

Cali

1990-1991

 Advising various businesses related to sugar mills in the area of Information Systems.

### **ACADEMIC HONORS**

#### **ICESI University**

- Monitor- Mathematics I
- Monitor- Physics II (Electromagnetism)
- Teaching Assistant Data Structures in Turbo Pascal

### **Universidad de Los Andes**

Monitor- Quantitative Methods (Probability Theory)-MBA

• Graduate Assistant Research, "Systems Theory Applied to Organizations".

### **PAPERS**

# IV INTERNATIONAL FINANCE SYMPOSIUM Invited Speaker.

"Coherent Measures of Risk and TailVaR" Cartagena-Colombia, 20 -22 June 22, 2007